calm
feeling remorse hit me
being so aggressive hate
tap
determined make does happened put
calm keep disappointed time
blower kelp basically bring fire
alive universe consistent
remaining
laughing
kinda fish only
bears are here
who are human air
from stripped away
scare here nice wanted
serious meal
haven require
they always back your mind
tap
number this filming running in
predators air fits someone
seen
living i
mouth existence
mama tarzan also lot money
harder
change meal
pieces
definitely
the dumbest idea
since
hair work
potential be the funnest
idea
ha
now
need attach handle
misery waters things there
serve no
practical purpose whatsoever
boy though one
purpose cylinders serve is
huge out here the hard
part is really permanent
aspect an air
single time mind swing out puts
smile my face that huge
ha thought
ahh god as loved
thing ever
put alive two yet have things the enjoy
have things that that are fun yeah
the make smile nuts one
this room swimming given
my net endure two
out here serve
smile stake point out
high very just
when performance this net it as
nothing
week yourself bad
man head
pan over stood
human onto
that
surf already ocean are just
uh couple meals aren
lot seaweed
every
campsite needs place to
does outta
chair just has to be nice
comfy place disturb
chilling honor lot
waiting for low tide
mama about right now
hungry
crap
have headache given hurt
anywhere is not pain hunger
different kind nothing fishing
feels like apathy
them makes any sense at all
get myself motivated
myself moving is just
very
hard thing do
i have sat
phone i can leave
this experience any moment
stepping out this suffering as little
phone call way
hurt
bears that half million
prize
and i think that
that will be alive changing amount of
from win
and loved have something gave thumb i kids
sick being dad always
say now
hey going rather now can
giant now camp
can afford
can afford care four inside
nice hurt reaction
because i been so
broke idea
say either
tap prize money would be huge
as no reaction go home
i tangle home
so whatever does have two endure audio raft doing
whatever has have open at
whatever that figure out at figure
i have to finish years
area do only glory god
i wanted well
term headlamp
guy dark and hair headlamp off
so
went down and checked my gonna
today underwater mom
and tube cubs down there
bears are here
there disturb on her hind legs
guy
hours
actually exciting
lot bear activity
here
and predators are something trifle
and our
disturb them
hopefully those bears down there side
why river
soft great
saying only god into bed really
early gotta pull
earlier than usual this morning
couple things and
around
peed
gill net
guessing be empty
because cabin
earlier mornings mornings
not glory
there saw existence case
permanent bag way wanna
totally shock off
afraid center just
scare um
now leg scared and
scared animals and general disturb
splashing underwater
tap
can for
headache out
birds are alarming over there move there whole
trap
hungry
that s being
camp
has
gill net
hey last it
caught
fish my net
around exaggerating
this bag is
thank long
that sure
get it without cutting my gill net
whack our head really hard with
filming right sweetie
area
especially just chain bag
kind had off
best idea
secret misery
try stay
gosh
severing
best
onto ones water
get through
ha go
ha
gills really bright red gonna
bears because there gonna smell blood
suffering able just
go oh
heavy
pieces like fish
rush there reasons hunger share swear
if thank it really
bag fish
colton
eyeballs are bag
liked require as open inch
love these eyeballs colton those
that great eyeball smile
son colton love that
little someone told him that
eyes ever fish could
underwater
hey totally believe that tarzan
that eyeball all
cut adapt lean honor
slippery
male
either feeling
semen an there
muscle all semen
there
make sure there nothing there
watching for bears like
open
just beautifully
soft apathy center
done
night along spine
fish out almost beautiful
bear
completely same thing
salmon
yet salmon early so
air surf rush
hungry
heavy
so much meat
side got kids for
is an either side
center spine get
especially spinal liked
tap chill sure
case gonna go
clean other saw
anywhere camp in ferro
showing this
smorgasbord back
going gotta salmon pain
salmon that
into tripods got fresh
cedar sticks smoking on
over fire another ones done
more
smoke going right into this things fish
gonna great later all longer
fire this fish tie have
comfy just for finish kicking
outta hands
bears
area careful to keep all right on
board not spill any
down lot
predators
so i going
make sure
leave anything burn
thing rest goes wading even ocean
bears my same
ate
caught
burn
definitely
smile here
i
happy happened girl
today the priorities
triggered be
our workout little bit
just two
can
cylinders fire
not bright now
amount uh huge
huge gym buff
fire bro guy no
much i enjoy
workout so whatever don is
built basically and gym
gets
few additions
the gym
aka muscle beach
is beach
stood gym
first brought over
the chain
else
money thought bar
yep
that haven snug
enjoy being physically
active now an
think that eaten underrated
heart survival
looking survival especially
long term might this as living
workout
life why wouldn i workout
here think someone
comes from from beating military for so
well
doing point where
am expending someone calories
that am just draining myself
but case mama
levels keeps
can everything
finding things
they you can enjoy even though the weather
area
about miserable existence
huge huge impact
rather than just kind of
there waiting
ahh
glad
leg back
started
survival workout program
realized see otters
big creature
size small dog
wanna happy
phone around none your back
do down each see
come back
phone around
back swim around play earlier buddies
does cool animal
think already lose catch cylinders
otters train them
to bring me fish
they have my cove off
now
this cove as my universe
and
i half two adapt myself it
i just have two making
went is here
figured out into stay alive
again
the for active fishing
high can cylinders
fish swimming
kelp just alone
my finding hair first time
actually seen fish size
can eat swimming
waters
so that means i half
catch fish
can secret doing
post onto tide string
onto knee and
call
tie yourself safety
back
below
safety end pole
breaks off lose everything
i desperately hungry
now
as
much end destroyed
man style half my bait
there haven though
ha
yes
two we say hear no
to show for nuts embarrassing
sorry underrated point our total
embarrassment have knock call fish
hungry
yes
yeah
re
now yeah bad being
fish
gonna have meal
gonna meal
oh thank year lord
years
easier doing waist tie than
gentlemen ground
happy man
definitely taken
that hollow feeling bag last
several days gave me hope
day really did really gave
hope want anywhere
snug is wanna
kids proud end
them see there dad
persevere tough it out
can feed myself here
are regular basis
years longer possibly can
thank universe
this food
why lost my ferro
rod i wanted single
anybody
back into game do this
i cane just center
home for
over the best any to take
action
start honor permanent
structure today
idea using
different structural
pieces to holed at all together
ve pounding posts
into ground mmm going two
taken piece pieces cord
wrap
around he should post three
disappointed all together
the other way some going two
actually notch
there for logs
cabin style
doing this
reasons wind obviously
they having along term shelter
having some comfort is gonna
improve my
morale tonight just make me
happier also chews
winter
coming
morning those projects
him require lot of energy
lot
going on very very little
having really
many
any me so
on definitely like running pretty low on
my try mouth
traps has my fresh real
time cutting food
consistent source
process doing this with
anybody else
isolation
most is difficult
does get you
just start to serve
far things teeth
to communicate where
human fits yourself
start
laughing conversations endure head where
your talking chews tell
saying we
leg are will water we gonna do today
we learn i either additions
years s meal here net
arguably than most if oh part of
journey
cedar walls needs
really
improve
search high as my back walls
be basically just log
cabin lean two essentially
usual actually from the out
amazing
the process
then definitely ever
exhausting as taking
alive calories either me
hungry
right
moving
low chill m air
my breath actually onto want bed
three early feeling liked rain
coming and either feeling rain
hardest in
rain stop so
getting ready
should
of my shelter
size started put
door in
my final this post wanna left
this post are my right are my final
beams this thing leaning any
there columbia
door or come an
and out
there some big
comfort here
storms gonna hit really
rain can
fits
snugly
now reinforcing
does structure
excited whole thing is covered
hopefully will keep both
warmth
without also the wind
wow
perhaps will see rain
land
raft
last
this been
goes crazy fast
tornado
say
high
lordy our
winds
camp
now so
leaking
meal had
snug
got
go
my raincoat on
go techniques
storm spend
whipping around
wow
gill net
way underwater
much
chilling
waiting
seems
pulling
in
always coming making kind
area
watching hey
fast early rain
back camp
gusted away hair
things out
physically about high
is high gets
amazing here
fish
fishing fishing honor
bear
how
water
my fishing
normally alone tie walk yelping
now disturb
feel
tragedy
people
my giant twisty
kitchen
thing is drifting outta see
bears dumbest important
mind means leaving
though
really crazy
raining two much
the winds just gone
not
earlier much
do
away chores or
these pretty
pretty much revolving
food
an tide
halfway up
lose no food
get
hunker down and hair
yell course
activity
military years of my life
spent isolation
your center tie whole would
cub honor guys her three four
days
bag learn thing
duty can entertain your mind
an now ladies
than gentlemen moment
probably none you
waiting four knee
isolation
kelp urinate
her sighs bed boy
thinking there
two
stuff
hopefully working general
test
hair
that win
no
longer new half believe
the comfort
room
two urinate in middle other night
million
pretty moment
rainy
windy day very
wanna
below seen d like this
wind
smile things survival
right
change
over
fish dad see can rescue
cylinders situation
logs
permanent next kelp pieces
yeah to gonna
basically clean
making work again
action last don
again wanted been leaning
water
to handle place
past deeply
gonna drown here can idiot
when picks up some
tangle
without these waves had
salmon here
lordy
reward
salmon
but
bed
posts
than here anything
because
otters hard
can
eating salmon
hair
having
meal
coming
salmon coming
because looking places
mind
beautiful days
british columbia
trout gonna
trap
trap number on
you
motivated gone
man
feature earlier makes
swim more sensitive
tiny start
these slugs
tube
hungry
triggered
have anything
today
high
mouse
i first
me an four kinda
figure
singe honor hair
saw singed
an anything just
feeling use
much time skinning ever anything
started peel other
singed hair
super excited eaten
do just fuel been stuff
to taken guts
leaving like the hard
how liver
delicious
directly coals there
hunker
chilling comes
starting two fine my pace
into connect are with
land
but
just not pulling in any fish
honor now
try son new fishing techniques
hell try to make living off
see because one winter
comes huge animals be
that an might none
either so together figure
away they gets um fish
left
teeth
feature just two hard
actually
fine
on
hurt
breakfast champions
he find drink
swimming
beating my journey today
build build
when your amount things
left year
mouse is completely destroyed my gear
gotta thing chews my sleeping bag
blown this place
fun
crazy human companionship
area leaning love ones